SAI **GUTTA**

sairao77@gmail.com

https://www.linkedin.com/in/saigutta https://sairao77.github.io

Microsoft Certified Office 365 Administrator with over 6+ years of experience in Windows Server Management, SharePoint Administration, End-User support, configuring and maintaining cloud computing solutions like Office 365, and Azure. Looking to leverage my knowledge and experience as a Cloud Solutions Architect.

EXPERIENCE

MAY 2013 - PRESENT

PROGRAMMER ANALYST II, MMS HOLDINGS INC.

- Global Administrator Office 365
 - SharePoint Online Administration
- Azure Active Directory
- Teams & Skype For Business Administration

- Exchange Online Administration
- Azure AD Connect
- Protection and Security Compliance

- Azure Tenant Administrator
 - Windows Virtual Desktop
- Azure App Service
- Compute (Virtual Machine)

Storage Account

Virtual Network (Firewall, Load Balancer, Application Gateway, VPN Gateway)

- Cost Management
- Migration, Upgrade, and Hybrid Infrastructure
 - O Data migration of SharePoint on-premises (2003, 2007, 2010, 2013) to SharePoint Online
 - Exchange hybrid setup and migration of mailbox to Exchange Online
- Upgrade SharePoint 2010 to 2013
- Regular installation of cumulative updates for Exchange 2013

- Others
 - Active Directory, DHCP & DNS
 - Group Policy Object
 - VMware Horizon Cloud
 - VMware vCenter VM Management
 - Network Storage Management
- Zendesk Administration
- Change Management
- TrendMicro
- O Windows Desktop 7, 8, 8.1, 10 Management
- O Barracuda Backup & Backup Exec Administration and Maintenance
- GoDaddy & Network Solutions account

 - o Identity Life Cycle Management

JAN 2012 - MAY 2013

GRADUATE ASSISTANT, EASTERN MICHIGAN UNIVERSITY

- Website Administrator Maintain Computer Science Dept. website built on PHP and MySQL
- C, C++, Java Tutor
- Teaching Assistant for C++ and Java courses

EDUCATION

MAY 2013

M.S. COMPUTER SCIENCE

EASTERN MICHIGAN UNIVERSITY, MI, U.S.A.

GPA: 3.85

MAY 2011

B. TECH INFORMATION TECHNOLOGY

ANNA UNIVERSITY, TN, INDIA.

GRADE: FIRST CLASS WITH DISTINCTION

SKILLS

- Office 365 Administration
- Windows Active Directory
- Azure Administration

- Windows Server Management
- PowerShell Automation
- HTML and JavaScripting
- Team Work & Communication
- Project Lead
- End-User Support

CERTIFICATION

- Microsoft Certified: Azure Administrator Associate
- Microsoft Certified Solutions Associate Office 365
- Microsoft 365 Certified: Teams Administrator Associate





